<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- This is an automatically generated file. -->
<Chapter Label="Chapter_Introduction">
<Heading>Introduction</Heading>

 Let <Math>G</Math> be a subgroup of the regular rooted k-tree, <Math>\textrm{Aut}(T_{k})</Math> with its group action, <Math>\alpha</Math>, defined as <Math>\alpha(g,x)=g(x)</Math>, where <Math>g\in G</Math> are the automorphisms of <Math>G</Math> and <Math>x\in X</Math> the vertices of <Math>T_{k}</Math>. Let <Math>\textrm{stab}_{G}(0)=\{g\in G : \alpha(g,0) = 0\}</Math>, and <Math>T_0\subset T_{k}</Math> be the set of all vertices below and including the vertex 0. Additonally, let <Math>\varphi_0 : \textrm{stab}_G(0)\rightarrow G</Math> be a group homomorphism with the mapping <Math>g\mapsto g|_{T_0}</Math>. Then <Math>G</Math> is called self-replicating if and only if the following two conditions, <Math>\mathcal{R}_k</Math>, are satisfied: <Math>G</Math> is vertex transitive on level 1 of <Math>T_{k}</Math>, and <Math>\varphi_0\left(\textrm{stab}_{G}(0)\right)=G</Math>.
<P/>
 A group <Math>G\leq\mathrm{Aut}(T_{k})</Math> acting greater than level 1 is said to have sufficient rigid automorphisms if for each pair of vertices <Math>u</Math> and <Math>v</Math> on level <Math>1</Math> of the tree, <Math>T_{k,1}</Math>, there exists an automorphism <Math>g\in G</Math> such that <Math>g(u)=v</Math> and <Math>g|_u=e</Math>, where <Math>g</Math> is called <Math>(u,v)</Math>-rigid. For a self-replicating group <Math>G</Math> on level <Math>n</Math> of the tree, <Math>T_{k,n}</Math>, with sufficient rigid automorphisms, the maximal extension of <Math>G</Math>, <Math>\mathcal{M}(G)</Math>, is the largest self-replicating group (not necessarily with sufficient rigid automorphisms) on <Math>\textrm{Aut}(T_{k,n+1})</Math> that projects onto <Math>G</Math>, defined as:
 <Display>\mathcal{M}(G):= \{x\in\mathrm{Aut}(T_{k,n+1}) : \varphi_{n+1}(x)\in G and x|_v\in G \textrm{for all v on level 1}\}.</Display>
 The self-replicating property is preserved across conjugacy. For a group <Math>H\leq\mathrm{Aut}(T_{k,n})</Math> with sufficient rigid automorphisms, and a self-replicating group <Math>G\leq\mathrm{Aut}(T_{k,n+1})</Math>, there exists a conjugate of <Math>G</Math> in <Math>\mathrm{Aut}(T_{k,n+1})</Math> with sufficient rigid automorphisms. Since groups on level 1 inherently have sufficient rigid automorphisms, then self-replicating groups with sufficient rigid automorphisms can be found on all levels of the tree.
<P/>
 The <Package>SRGroups</Package> package serves to provide a library of these self-replicating groups to further the ongoing studies of infinite networks and group theory. By using the above definitions and conditions, several GAP methods and functions have been built to allow computations of these groups and expand the understanding of their behaviour.
<P/>
 First, this package acts as a library for searching currently known self-replicating groups for varying degrees and levels of regular rooted trees. This package also acts as a regular GAP package with functions that allow the expansion of the library and addition of attributes/properties relevant to self-replicating groups. Additional functions also exist in this package that are compatible with GraphViz, to plot diagrams of the extension behaviour of these self-replicating groups and their corresponding Hasse diagrams at different depths.
<Section Label="Chapter_Introduction_Section_Purpose">
<Heading>Purpose</Heading>

 To do.
</Section>


</Chapter>

